<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Sandeep&#39;s World</title>
    <link>/en/series/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Sandeep&#39;s World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyleft © 2021-{year} Sandeep Kumar.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 22:13:43 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/series/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Interfaces</title>
      <link>/en/posts/interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 22:13:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/posts/interfaces/</guid>
      <description>How to use interfaces in Go? Just as many human-based languages exist, There are dozens of programming languages used in the industry today to communicate with computers. Each language has its own distinct features, though many times there are some similarities between programming languages. If you wish/need to master a programming language, you might wonder which one to learn.After all, it will take time to learn the language, so everyone want to make the right choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rienforcement Learning to develop AI agents</title>
      <link>/en/posts/rienforcement-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/posts/rienforcement-learning/</guid>
      <description>Rienforcement Learning to develop AI agents Reinforcement learning (RL) is an area of machine learning concerned with how intelligent agents ought to take actions in an environment in order to maximize the notion of cumulative reward.Reinforcement learning is one of three basic machine learning paradigms, alongside supervised learning and unsupervised learning.
Reinforcement learning differs from supervised learning in not needing labelled input/output pairs be presented, and in not needing sub-optimal actions to be explicitly corrected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>getting insights into various programming languages</title>
      <link>/en/posts/programming-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/posts/programming-languages/</guid>
      <description>I am writing this blog during my summer project on gaining insight into different programming languages ​​and understanding different paradigms of programming.
    General Concepts- Here is a quick overview on Fundamentals of Programming Languages : Similar to human interface languages, which have their own set of rules that have to be followed in order to write correctly in that language, programming languages ​​also follow certain rules.Classification of programming languages on the basis of -</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
