<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Sandeep&#39;s World</title>
    <link>/en/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Sandeep&#39;s World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyleft © 2021-{year} Sandeep Kumar.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:02:19 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Things to Explore in College</title>
      <link>/en/posts/things-to-explore-in-college/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:02:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/posts/things-to-explore-in-college/</guid>
      <description>Things to explore in college I&amp;rsquo;m writing this after reading a fascinating blog of nehchal(Y11). Thanking him for providing such creating such ideas. Being always step ahead in typos, Forgive me if you find any.
Later or soon you will be kicked out of the campus. College life is cheerful and indeed the most beautiful But it can be dreadful at the same time. Memories of which shall linger in your heart, forever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All About SSH</title>
      <link>/en/posts/all-about-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 11:53:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/posts/all-about-ssh/</guid>
      <description>SSH and how it enables secure data-sharing Note: This is intended as future notes to myself, but I hope you learn something from it too!
Come back soon to read complete blog&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competitve Programming</title>
      <link>/en/posts/cp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 01:05:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/posts/cp/</guid>
      <description>Competitive Coding Resources Here are some CP resources that I found useful.
Why did I write this blog?  Good question! There are plenty of resources out there on how to start competitive programming but what I found missing there were proper links to resources. I also had selfish reasons:- I wanted a short description, which nevertheless contained the major ideas underlying the algorithms, a discussion of their relative strengths and weaknesses, with hints on what is known (and not known, but would be good to know) about these algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feature of Scala</title>
      <link>/en/posts/feature-of-scala/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 10:09:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/posts/feature-of-scala/</guid>
      <description>A short interpretation on some superb features of Scala. I&amp;rsquo;m writting this microblog while learning Scala as a part of my SnT project (gaining insight into different programming languages ​​and understanding different paradigms of programming.)
Scala The name is an acronym from &amp;lsquo;Scala&amp;rsquo;able Language. As it&amp;rsquo;s purpose of introduction was to resolve scalability issues. The evolution of traditional languages such as Java, C#, and C++ has slowed down considerably, and programmers who are eager to use more modern language features are looking elsewhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interfaces</title>
      <link>/en/posts/interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 22:13:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/posts/interfaces/</guid>
      <description>How to use interfaces in Go? Just as many human-based languages exist, There are dozens of programming languages used in the industry today to communicate with computers. Each language has its own distinct features, though many times there are some similarities between programming languages. If you wish/need to master a programming language, you might wonder which one to learn.After all, it will take time to learn the language, so everyone want to make the right choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operating Systems</title>
      <link>/en/posts/operating-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 08:21:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/posts/operating-systems/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Linux Operating Systems. It&amp;rsquo;s worth writing everything you do. Maybe you learned something new in the version control system, or fixed something in your operating system. As similar problems become convenient if you have solutions to problems already encountered. Ofc this also preserve your interest.
This blog mainly consists of my learnings and experiences about operating systems. The story of having multiple OS&amp;rsquo;s on my machine. Also why I prefer linux kernel over Windows</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown Syntax Guide</title>
      <link>/en/posts/markdown-syntax/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/posts/markdown-syntax/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Markdown is a way to style text on the web. You control the display of the document; formatting words as bold or italic, adding images, and creating lists are just a few of the things we can do with Markdown. Mostly, Markdown is just regular text with a few non-alphabetic characters thrown in, like # or *.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use Markdown most places around GitHub:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Gists
Comments in Issues and Pull Requests
Files with the .md or .markdown extension
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article offers a sample of basic Markdown syntax that can be used in Hugo content files, also it shows whether basic HTML elements are decorated with CSS in a Hugo theme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog102</title>
      <link>/en/posts/blog102/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/posts/blog102/</guid>
      <description>Hey ,Glad you are here :Slightly Smiling Face: I’m Sandeep Kumar, a undergrad student in Computer Science and Engineering at IIT Kanpur,(class of 2024). Since the endsem exams of my second semester ended today {in my bedroom on a random Sunday at 11:10 AM :Slightly Frowning Face: } I thought of posting programming stuffs and general life experience as well. So I chose to make my own blog manager.Based on my experience and working with peers I loved to give you an overview.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>getting insights into various programming languages</title>
      <link>/en/posts/programming-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/posts/programming-languages/</guid>
      <description>I am writing this fun blog while learning different Programming Languages as a part of my college project (gaining insight into different programming languages ​​and understanding different paradigms of programming.)
    General Concepts- Here is a quick overview on Fundamentals of Programming Languages : Similar to human interface languages, which have their own set of rules that have to be followed in order to write correctly in that language, programming languages ​​also follow certain rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rienforcement Learning to develop AI agents</title>
      <link>/en/posts/rienforcement-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/posts/rienforcement-learning/</guid>
      <description>Rienforcement Learning to develop AI agents Reinforcement learning (RL) is an area of machine learning concerned with how intelligent agents ought to take actions in an environment in order to maximize the notion of cumulative reward.Reinforcement learning is one of three basic machine learning paradigms, alongside supervised learning and unsupervised learning.
Reinforcement learning differs from supervised learning in not needing labelled input/output pairs be presented, and in not needing sub-optimal actions to be explicitly corrected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emoji Support</title>
      <link>/en/posts/emoji-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/posts/emoji-support/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Emoji can be enabled in a Hugo project in a number of ways.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
